indianweddingcard.in 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy : Social Media Examiner

**Last Updated on** : December 18, 2018

Social Media Examiner is committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to our website, subscribers to our newsletters, and those providing contact information. In addition, Social Media Examiner is opposed to unauthorized commercial e-mail delivery, otherwise known as spam. Please read the following Privacy and Spam Policy to understand how your personal information is treated. From time to time, Social Media Examiner may offer new information or services that may affect this policy. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy and Spam Policy, please send an e-mail to [privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com](mailto:privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com). Spam abuses can be notified at [abuse@socialmediaexaminer.com](mailto:abuse@socialmediaexaminer.com).

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT & HOW IS IT USED?**

> **Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website** : We may collect personal information from you such as your name or e-mail address. For example, you may voluntarily submit personal information to Social Media Examiner by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form. In addition, upon making certain purchases described herein, we may ask you to create a user profile, which would allow you to create a username and password. We will store the username, but your password will not be visible in our records.
> 
> **Information We Collect from Others** : We may receive information about you from other sources. For example, if you use a third-party software through the site, they may transfer information to us for fulfillment.
> 
> **Automatically-Collected Information** : We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access Social Media Examiner. For example, when you use Social Media Examiner, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using Social Media Examiner, such as links clicked.
> 
> **Cookies** : We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by Social Media Examiner. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the website.

The following list includes examples of specific ways we collect personal information from our website visitors and the type of information collected:

> **Electronic Newsletter** : To register online for our electronic newsletters, we request the following required information: (i) name, and (ii) e-mail address. The provision of an e-mail address is mandatory in order to receive our newsletter.
> 
> **Contact Forms** : To contact Social Media Examiner for the purposes of evaluating or engaging our services or to answer your questions, we utilize numerous forms throughout our site. Required information varies depending on the form and at most includes (i) name, and (ii) e-mail address. The provision of this information is mandatory in order to receive a response from Social Media Examiner. The provision of the remaining information requested on the registration form is optional.
> 
> **Online Purchases** : When you purchase a product from Social Media Examiner, we may utilize a third-party online shopping system, which is described more fully below. To process your payment, certain standard required information includes address and credit card information. Transactions are secured via SSL encryption and credit card details will never be e-mailed. Credit information is purged from our systems on a regular basis.

**HOW YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE USED**

Social Media Examiner may use your personal information in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the website;
  * To create your account, identify you as a user of the website, and customize the website to your account;
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each e-mail newsletter will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings by unsubscribing;
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative e-mails, confirmation e-mails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries;
  * To provide you with user support;
  * To track and measure website performance;
  * To process payment for purchases you make through Social Media Examiner;
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity;
  * To review the effectiveness of our marketing programs and analyze other general demographic trends;
  * To notify you of new information or services that may be of interest to you; or,
  * To send promotional materials.

**DOES SOCIAL MEDIA EXAMINER SHARE MY INFORMATION?**

Social Media Examiner will not share, rent, or sell your personally identifiable information with third-parties. We may, however, share your information with third-parties when we are authorized to share such information.

Additionally, Social Media Examiner may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policy. Social Media Examiner currently uses the following third-party service providers:

> **Tracking** : Social Media Examiner uses various marketing tools that help us create a better user experience for people visiting our site. These tools allow us to look at aggregated data such as scrolling patterns, clicks, and allow us to run tests to determine which pages result in the best actions. However, your personally identifiable information is not used by any of these tools. We use the following third-party service providers for tracking:
> 
> Hotjar: [Privacy policy](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy), [cookie information](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/cookie-information)
> 
> VWO: [Privacy policy](https://vwo.com/privacy-policy/), [opt-out](https://vwo.com/opt-out/)
> 
> Google Analytics: [Privacy Policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)
> 
> **Remarketing** : Social Media Examiner uses remarketing tracking cookies and conversion pixels from vendors such as Google and Facebook to present special offers to you for our products or services over the Google Content Network and via social networks. This means you may see an ad for one of our products or services as a result of visiting our website. In addition, Social Media Examiner uses custom audiences based on e-mails and phone numbers of subscribers and customers. This allows us to present special offers for our products and services to you via Facebook and Google. However, your personally identifiable information is not used by any remarketing service other than to present you special offers from us. We use the following third-party service providers for remarketing:
> 
> Facebook: [Opt-out of Facebook remarketing here](http://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217)
> 
> Google: [Opt-out of Google remarketing here](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en)
> 
> **Newsletters** : Social Media Examiner uses Drip as its e-mail service provider. Drip collects contact information, distributes our newsletter, and tracks actions you take that assist us in measuring the performance of the website and newsletters. Upon subscription, Drip also tracks the pages you visit on the website. If you become a customer, information about the products you purchase is passed into Drip.
> 
> Our newsletters contain tracking pixels. This pixel is embedded in e-mails and allows us to analyze the success of our newsletters. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an e-mail, which links within the e-mail you click, and the pages you visit on our website. This behavior is not passed to third-parties. All data submitted at the time of subscription to our newsletter is stored on Drip’s servers. [You may access Drip’s privacy policy here](https://www.drip.com/privacy). At any time, you may be removed from our newsletter list by clicking on the unsubscribe button provided in each e-mail.
> 
> We may also rely on a third-party service, OptinMonster, to service certain pop-up subscription boxes. Any information collected by OptinMonster is passed through directly to Drip and is not stored by any party other than Drip.
> 
> **Chatbots** : Social Media Examiner uses ManyChat as its Facebook Messenger chatbot. Ma _nyChat collects public Facebook profile information, distributes our content, and tracks actions you take that assist us in measuring the performance of the chatbot.[You may access ManyChat’s privacy policy here](https://manychat.com/privacy.html). _
> 
> _Upon subscription, the actions that you take in the chatbot are passed through to Dashbot. Dashbot helps us measure the performance of the chatbot with analytics.  [You may access Dashbot’s privacy policy here.](https://www.dashbot.io/legal/privacy)_  
>  _We may also rely on a third-party service, Integromat, to capture your email and other public Facebook profile information from ManyChat, and pass it through to Drip.  [You may access Integromat’s privacy policy here.](https://www.integromat.com/en/kb/privacy.html)_
> 
> **Purchases** : Social Media Examiner uses 1ShoppingCart, Stripe, and PayPal to service payments for some services.
> 
> **_• 1ShoppingCart_** collects personal information such as your name, e-mail address, address, and payment information. All data entered into 1ShoppingCart is stored on 1ShoppingCart’s site. [Click here for their Privacy Policy](http://www.1shoppingcart.com/shopping-cart-terms-privacy.asp). All payments processed through 1ShoppingCart use PayPal Payflow. This service stores your name, amount of your purchase, and payment details on their site. PayPal Payflow is governed by [PayPal’s Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full). Upon making a purchase through 1ShoppingCart, you will receive e-mail confirmations to the e-mail address you provide during your purchase. These e-mails are sent through various services as outlined below.
> 
> **_• Stripe_** collects personal information such as your name, e-mail address, zip code, and payment information. [You may access Stripe’s Privacy Policy here](https://stripe.com/us/privacy/). Upon making a purchase via Stripe, your will receive e-mail confirmations to the e-mail address you provide during your purchase. These e-mails are sent through various services as outlined below.
> 
> _**• PayPal**_ collects personal information such as your name, e-mail address, address, and payment information. [You may access PayPal’s Privacy Policy here](https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full). Upon making a purchase via Stripe, your will receive e-mail confirmations to the e-mail address you provide during your purchase. These e-mails are sent through various services as outlined below.
> 
> **Social Media Marketing World** : Social Media Examiner hosts an annual conference, Social Media Marketing World. If you purchase tickets for Social Media Marketing World, you will enter personal data into Amember for processing this transaction. Your payment will be processed by Stripe or PayPal, as described above. Information you provide at the time of purchase will be used for creation of conference badges and to invite you to join a group on LinkedIn. E-mails regarding your purchase may be transmitted through Amazon SES, which does not store your personal information. We communicate with conference attendees via e-mail through Drip, which stores the product you purchased and your personal contact information on their servers. [You may access Drip’s privacy policy here](https://www.drip.com/privacy).
> 
> **Online Summits** : Social Media Examiner hosts regular online events (“Summits”). If you purchase tickets for one of these Summits, you will enter personal data into Amember for processing this transaction. Your payment will be processed by Stripe or PayPal, as described above. Emails regarding your purchase may be transmitted through Amazon SES, which does not store your personal information. We communicate with Summit attendees via e-mail through Drip, which stores the product you purchased and your personal contact information on their servers. [You may access Drip’s privacy policy here](https://www.drip.com/privacy).
> 
> **Social Media Marketing Society** : Social Media Examiner hosts a paid membership site, the Social Media Marketing Society. If you purchase a membership in the Social Media Marketing Society, your purchase will be processed through 1ShoppingCart, as described above.
> 
> Additionally, at the time you join the Social Media Marketing Society, you will create a profile through Wishlist Member, which stores your personal information on our servers. We communicate with Social Media Marketing Society Members via e-mail through Aweber, which stores your personal contact information on their servers. [Aweber’s privacy policy may be viewed here](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm).
> 
> **Surveys** : Periodically, we may invite you to complete a voluntary survey. All surveys are completed through Survey Monkey. All survey responses may be submitted anonymously and only your IP address is stored. You may voluntarily enter your name and e-mail address. All data submitted through Survey Monkey is stored on their servers and is subject to the [Survey Monkey privacy policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/).
> 
> **Webinars** : From time to time, Social Media Examiner or the Social Media Marketing Society will host webinars, which are hosted through Demio, GoToWebinar or Crowdcast. If you elect to participate in a webinar, you will be required to submit personal information to register and login. You may also receive e-mail communications regarding reminders and playback availability.
> 
> All information submitted for your participation is stored by the software hosting the webinar. Please consult their individual privacy policies.
> 
> Demio: [Privacy Policy](https://demio.com/privacy-policy)
> 
> GoToWebinar: [Privacy Policy](https://www.logmeininc.com/legal/privacy)
> 
> Crowdcast: [Privacy Policy](https://www.crowdcast.io/privacy-policy)
> 
> **Contact Information and Website Support** : We offer multiple ways to contact Social Media Examiner, including contact forms, e-mails, and chat. If at any time, you attempt to contact us through a contact form, the information you provide will be stored on our servers. If you submit a form or email us, we use FreshDesk to process all these inquiries and track responses. All related information is stored on the servers at FreshDesk, in accordance with the [FreshDesk privacy policy](https://www.freshworks.com/privacy/?_ga=2.180940391.1341746022.1529441046-1062430173.1529441046). If you use our live chat feature, it is powered by FreshChat, and your communication will be stored on servers at FreshDesk (the company behind FreshChat), in accordance with the [FreshDesk privacy policy](https://www.freshworks.com/privacy/?_ga=2.180940391.1341746022.1529441046-1062430173.1529441046). If you use the chatbot feature, it will be stored on the servers of FlowXO, in accordance with the [FlowXO privacy policy](https://flowxo.com/privacy).
> 
> **Comments** : Social Media Examiner uses Disqus to make it easy for you to leave comments on blog posts. Personal information that you enter for comments will be stored on the Disqus servers, in accordance with the [Disqus privacy policy](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy).

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in Social Media Examiner’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your e-mail address(es) or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through Social Media Examiner to third-parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

**ANONYMOUS DATA  
******From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

**PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION** **  
** If you create a user profile on Social Media Examiner or the Social Media Marketing Society or leave a comment on Social Media Examiner, certain information may be publicly visible.

**COOKIES** **  
** Social Media Examiner uses cookies to: store visitors’ preferences; record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit; ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads; or customize our content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

At any time, you may prevent the setting of cookies by the website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of Social Media Examiner may be entirely usable.

**WHAT IF THERE ARE CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY AND SPAM POLICY?  
**If we change our Privacy and Spam Policy, we will post those changes on our privacy page at https://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/privacy/.

**RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

> **Opt-out** : You may opt-out of future e-mail communications by following the unsubscribe links in our e-mails. You may also notify us at [privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com](mailto:privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com) to be removed from our mailing list.
> 
> **Access** : You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to [privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com](mailto:privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com).
> 
> **Amend** : You may contact us at [privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com](mailto:privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com) to amend or update your personal information.
> 
> **Forget** : In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to [privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com](mailto:privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com).

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

**SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION  
**At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to Social Media Examiner. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy and Spam Policy.

**CHILDREN’S INFORMATION  
**Social Media Examiner does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that Social Media Examiner has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at [privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com](mailto:privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com) and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

**SPAM POLICY  
**Social Media Examiner is strongly opposed to spam. We will only send e-mail to users that have explicitly requested to receive an e-mail from Social Media Examiner. Examples may include:

  * Opt-in subscribers to the Social Media Examiner Newsletter
  * Users that complete a contact form
  * All communication will be related and relevant to what you have requested.

**WEB LINKS  
**Social Media Examiner contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Social Media Examiner is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site to read the privacy and spam policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy and Spam Policy applies solely to information collected by Social Media Examiner.

**HOW DO I CONTACT SOCIAL MEDIA EXAMINER?  
**If you have any further questions or comments regarding the Social Media Examiner website or this Privacy and Spam Policy, you may contact [privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com](mailto:privacy@socialmediaexaminer.com).

**LEGAL DISCLAIMER  
**We may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our site.
